mobileshop.com 2012-11-22

# Mobile Phones - Buy 3, 3G, o2, Orange, Vodafone, Virgin and T-Mobile and Accessories. MobileShop Cheap mobile phones deals

## MobileShop.com Privacy Policy

MobileShop.com is part of the A1 Comms group of companies.

The A1 Comms Group are committed in complying with the Data Protection Act 1998 so have published this Privacy Policy to help you understand what information we collect, how we use it and what your rights are.

We may pass information to associated companies within the A1 Comms Group. (A full list of the companies within the A1 Comms Group are available upon request) Please send your request to:

**Privacy & Data Controller**  
Mobileshop.com  
Contract House  
Turnpike Business Park  
Alfreton  
Derbyshire DE55 7AD

**What information is collected, and where is it obtained?**

We receive data directly from you at time of purchase (online application/order forms or via telephone), and when you enter a prize draw. Additional information can at times be obtained from third parties, such as the credit reference agencies used when applying for credit (for example pay monthly contract mobile phones).

Such information requested at time of purchase, enquiries or entries into a prize draw are dependant on what you purchase or are interested in purchasing or the prize draw entered into.

We also automatically collect information via electronic means, such as via Cookies (see below). We also obtain the IP (Internet Provider) address of users placing orders via our website(s) for security and fraud prevention reasons.

Any information collected within the A1 Comms Group is collected lawfully and in accordance with Data Protection Act 1998.

**What do we do with your information?**

\- Information you provide is used to fulfil your order, including the processing of payments.

\- For mobile phone applications we will pass information about you to service providers and credit reference agencies.

\- In cases where an order is part completed via our website(s), we may contact you to ascertain if you require any further assistance with placing your order.

\- We will disclose information about you to any relevant regulator if they require it or to anyone else if there is a legal duty to do so. 

\- We may record telephone conversations with you to ensure consistent service levels, to prevent or detect fraud and for training purposes.

\- Monitor customer traffic patterns and site usage to help develop and improve the layout of the site.

\- Notify you about enhancements to our services such as; changes to the website(s), new services and special offers, or competitions we think may be of interest to you. 

\- A1 Comms Group Ltd will use your information for their own marketing purposes and may also pass your personal information to other companies within the A1 Comms Group to use for their marketing. 

\- Members of the A1 Comms Group may contact you by mail, telephone, email, text message, or any other reasonable method.

\- You may receive contact from carefully selected third party companies, if you have stated that you are happy to receive such contact. You can select to receive or not receive such contact from third party companies during the ordering processes.

**Insurance Policies**

Any Mobile Phone Insurance Policy you select will be administrated by City Main Administrators Ltd. Your information may be used as detailed above and may also be passed to other companies connected to City Main Administrators Ltd (for insurance administration purposes and relevant regulators).

**Credit Applications**

Information which you provide will be used to search your record at the credit reference agencies as well as the electoral register through 3rd party services.

Even if your application goes no further, the credit reference agencies and the *service providers will add details of this search and your application to your record.

In assessing your credit record, we may also use any information which the A1 Comms Group already holds about you.

If your credit application is successful and we fulfil your order, you will be entered into a credit agreement with the Network Service Provider who will add details of your agreement as well as ongoing details of your account and how you manage it to credit reference agency records. 

If you do not repay on time, the Network Service Provider will inform the credit reference agencies who will record details of the debt. A1 Comms Group will also be informed, who will at this point issue an invoice to you for the retail cost of the items purchased.

All this information will be seen by other organisations carrying out later checks. The information may be used to assess you for credit or to verify your identity. 

For details of the Credit Reference Agencies that we receive information from and share information with; please write to our Data Controller (contact details above).

*Service Provider is the Mobile Phone Network in which you attempt to enter an agreement with, such as Vodafone, T-Mobile, Orange, Three and O2.

**Fraud Prevention**

In order to protect our customers and us from fraud and theft, we may pass on information that we obtain from making identity checks and other information in our customer records, to other companies within the A1 Comms Group, and to other 3rd party organisations (including law enforcement agencies) involved in fraud prevention and detection, to use in the same way; where there is sufficient evidence to suggest that fraud is being perpetrated.

We may use automated decision making systems when assessing you for credit and for fraud prevention as well as reputable 3rd party sources and may at times request proof of address and or identity before an application can be passed through our Order Verification Department.

**Consent**

By using our website, placing an order, or entering into a prize draw, you are consenting to the collection, processing and use of this information by us and other companies within the A1 Comms Group.

When you provide us with your information you will be given the opportunity to express your marketing preferences. 

We will always give you the opportunity to say whether you want to receive marketing emails from us by providing you with an 'opt out' or 'unsubscribe' option in any electronic marketing correspondence to enable you to stop any further mailings if you so wish.

We may also pass your information to other companies within the A1 Comms Group and to third parties for debtor tracing and debt recovery purposes. 

**Protection of Information**

We offer the use of a secure server for online ordering via our website(s), which encrypts all information before it is sent.

We will not request information which is excessive for the purposes of fulfilling on order; we will also delete any information which is no longer required within the reasonable period of time.

We will protect your data against unauthorised use by allowing only authorised employee's access to your personal information such as your Bank/Card details. For transmission of data and unauthorised access, these details will remain encrypted.

We follow strict procedures regarding storage and disclosure of information. These procedures mean you may be requested to provide proof of identity before any such information may be disclosed to you.

In some cases we may administer your account and provide other administrative functions and services from centres in countries outside of Europe. These countries do not always have the same standard of data protection laws as the UK. However, we will have a contract in place to ensure that your information is adequately secured and protected, and we will remain bound by our obligations under the Data Protection Act 1998, even when your personal information is processed outside of Europe.

**Accuracy of Information**

With your assistance, we will try our utmost to keep any information held about you up to date and accurate. If any of the information that we hold about you changes, such as your home addresses, names and e-mail addresses, then please contact us either by e-mail [privacy@mobileshop.com](mailto:privacy@mobileshop.com), or write to us at the address above.

You also have the right to request a copy of all the personal information we hold about you. To do this, write to our Data Controller (contact details above), enclosing a payment of �9.95 payable to MobileShop.com Ltd, to cover our administrative costs in dealing with your request. Include a valid proof of identity (e.g. copy of driving licence, passport etc) - contact us for a complete list. We need this proof to verify your identity before we can disclose any information to you.

We aim to respond to requests for information within 28 days or receiving the request, payment and suitable proof of identity. 

**Cookies**

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that are transferred to your computer's hard drive through your Internet Web browser to enable our systems to recognise your browser and to store items in your Shopping Trolley while using our website(s).

We also use Cookies to track and report the source of sales and user activity within our website(s).

**Comments**

If you have any comments or concern about privacy, please e-mail full details to [privacy@mobileshop.com](mailto:privacy@mobileshop.com) or write to the address above.
